晚上好 欢迎收看The Culpeper Minute
Good evening, and welcome to The Culpeper Minute.
自史上最畅销的自传- 《面罩之下》
It's been nearly a decade...
披露最初的蒙面英雄团体
...since the best-selling autobiography Under the Hood..
“新民兵”的秘密以来
evealed secrets of the original band of masked adventurers.
已有将近十年了
...the new Minutemen.
1975年 The Culpeper Minute刚在电视上播出时
In 1975, when The Culpeper Minute was new to the airwaves...
我们采访了《面罩之下》的作者——霍利斯·梅森
...we profiled the author of Under the Hood, Hollis Mason...
前任蒙面英雄 人称夜枭
...the former adventurer known as Nite Owl.
在我最初的报道在1975年播出时 《基恩法案》尚未通过
When my original report aired in 1975, the Keene Act had not yet been passed.
现在 这项有争议的法案禁止所有变装英雄和蒙面英雄的存在
考虑到目前围绕着蒙面正义这一主题的不安定局面
Given our current climate of unrest around the subject of masked justice...
我们认为重温当初的故事
t it would be interesting to revisit that origi
提醒大家整个变装英雄事迹的开端
...as a reminder of where the whole phenomena...
会十分有趣
...of costumed heroics began.
AN AUTOBIOGRAPHY
UNDER THE HOOD
今晚我们将与霍利斯·梅森谈论他的自传 《面罩之下》
霍利斯·梅森的回忆录揭露了一些
Hollis Mason's memoirs revealed some of the secrets...
关于蒙面英雄的秘密
...of the masked adventurers.
我与霍利斯在他最喜欢的纽约饭店the Gunga Diner见了面
I met with Hollis at one of his favorite New York establishments, the Gunga Diner.
在12岁时来到纽约
Coming to New York at 12 years old..
对我来说在很多方面都很梦幻
...it was, uh, fantastic for me in a lot of ways.
我的父亲在7号大街的弗农汽修店找到了一份工作
And my dad got a job at Vernon's Auto Repair off 7th Avenue.
现在是梅森汽修店了 对吧?
Now Mason's, right?
没错
同一个地方
然而你没有追随你父亲的脚步
你选择了另一条道路
是的 当我23岁时
MASON: Well, yeah, when I was 23..
我加入了纽约市警察局
joined the New York City Police Departmen
以及他灌输给我的价值观有很大的关系
因为在12岁以前很多时间是和我爷爷一起度过的
Because for the first 12 years of my life, I spent a lot of time with my grandda
他总是给我留下这样的印象
He was always keen to impress upon me...
乡下人在生活方式上比城市居民更道德
t country folk were morally healthier than city folk, the way they
当然在某些方面乡下人会存在竞争
Of course you were competitive in certain ways.
但他们也会互相帮助
But you were also -- You helped each other.
这是一种刻在我脑子里的道德观
当我第一次来到这座城市
看到的一些事情真的令我作呕
.there were things I saw that really filled me with disgust.
有些事我很难接受
有些到现在还是接受不了
Some of it I still can't.
我爷爷教给我的东西
What my grandfather gave me...
和我在这座城市面对的东西
...and what I was confronted with in the city-
当它们差距太大 我实在接受不了时
hen the distance between those things got too great and I couldn't deal with
我就会投入别的世界——流行小说的世界
hen I would go to my real other world, the world of pulp-fiction nove
它们描述了一个有着绝对价值观的世界
They described a world of absolute values...
那个世界的真善美从不受怀疑
..where what was good and true was never in doubt
而邪恶
总会受到应有的惩罚
这就是你追求的生活吗?
Is that how you've led your life, then?
这是我一直在努力实现的
That's what I've tried to do. Um....
没错
Yeah.
霍利斯·梅森 理想化的年轻警察
Hollis Mason, idealizing young cop...
试图理解他爷爷的乡村价值观
.trying to make sense of granddad's country values
以及他自己居住的大城市的粗犷
..and the grit of the big city he finds himself living in
很快 警察及其代表的司法正义就无法满足年轻的梅森了
Soon enough, the police force and its brand of justice is not enough for young Mason.
长期以来作为侦探小说和英雄主义漫画的粉丝
Long a fan of pulp detective fiction and comic-book heroics...
梅森做了别人只会幻想的事
..Mason did what others only fantasize about.
他给自己做了套伪装
He made himself a disguise...
并在夜间以义警的身份出没
...and set out in the nights as a vigilante..
并在夜之以警的身份出没
in the nighs as a vigilante...
..and set out
心警的身份出没
nights as a vigilante...
吉他自己的方式维护正义
是什么影响了梅森行为的转变?
What influenced this shift in Mason's behavior?
当你想起这个会觉得有趣
It's funny when you think about it.
我听说了所有的
You know, I've heard all the--
所有的笑话、谣言和影射
Ill the jokes and all the rumors and all the innuendos
对我来说真正重要的
What it really comes down to for me..
我来说重要的
What all comes down to for me.
来说 上環之!
Who real como for ine...
是我打給得像一只头鹰- 犯罪
...is that I dressed up like an owl and fought crime...
因为这很有趣
because it was fun.
因为这是作确的事
And because it was the right thing to do.
还有就是因为浅享受其中
And because: darn well enjoyed it.
我想我在1938年就开始有了这样的想法
我发现很多孩子都在看第一期动作漫画
COMPLETE STORY OF THE OR
我发现很多孩子都在看第一期动作漫画。
my bra there were LETE STORY OF THE DARING
THE COMPLETE OF VAL DREN
EXPLOITS OF THE ONE AND ONLY
我反现很多孩子都在看第一期动作漫画
Fids/Leading that firstissue of Action
我发现很多孩子都在看第一期动作漫画6
EXPLOITS OF THE ONE AND ONLY
STOPY OF THE DAPING
发现很多孩子都在看第
THE OFFE APR
there were a lot of kids reach that St issue of Act
THE COMPLETE STORY OF THE DARING
发现很多孩子都在看第一期动作漫画
there were a lot of kids reading that is issue of A-
THE COMPLETE STORY OF THE DARING
发现很多孩子都在着第一期动作漫画
我完全被吸引住了
我问了其中一个孩子能不能借我看看
asked one of the kids if could borrow it and take a look at
哇 真的震撼到我了
超人对你的影响最大 对很多孩子都是
Okay, Superman was your biggest influence, and it was to a lot of ki
但是你把它更进一步了
But you took it even further.
有一天我翻开报纸 一切都变了
MASON: Well, it all changed when i opened the newspaper one day...
有一天我翻开报纸一切都变了
我看到这些角色突破了他们的四色世界
saw that these characters had escaped from their four-color
and I saw that these characters had escaped from their four-color world
他们现在上了真正的头条新闻
and they were now in the factual black-and-white world of the headlines
NEW YORK, NY
被一个据说是从天而降到小巷
who supposedly dropped into the alleyway from abo
带着面具的人挫败了
...with something over his face.
他缴械了三个歹徒
nd he then proceeded to disarm the three attackers..
把他们三个人都揍到了医院
...and beat them with such severity that all three were hospitalized.
他是第一个蒙面义警
nd that was the first masked vigilante
当我听到这个改事的时候我就下定了决心
我将会是第二
...I was gonna be the second.
休息一下 马上回来
We have to take a break for our sponsors now, but when we come back...
我们有更多关于1975年的蒙面英雄的故事
...more from our 1975 story on masked adventurers.
我们现在继续回顾《面罩之下》
We return now to our retrospective look at Under the Hood..
以及在如今这些蒙面英雄对我们来说意味着什么
为什么你会想出猫头鹰服装?
CULPEPER: Why did you come up with the owl costume
这个想法的产生
MASON: It really came together...
是因为另一个跟我一起在警局工作的警察
because of another cop that I was working with in my station houl
他总是叫我下班后出去喝酒
And he kept asking me to go out for a beer after work.
我一直拒绝 因为我想在晚上训练
为我的另一份工作做好准备
...and get ready for my other career.
在仔准备
nd get ready
为我的另一份工作做好准备
...and get ready for my other career.
然后他开始叫我“夜枭”
And then he started calling me "night owl."
我喜欢这个名字 我想“好吧 就是它了 夜枭”
And I loved it. I thought, "Well, that's it, Nite Owl."
所以这个名字就是这么来的?
So that's where the name came from?
没错 这就是“夜枭”来源
Yeah. That's where it came from:
一旦有了名字 然后我就可以开始考虑服装的问题了
So once had the name, then I could start thinking about the costume
是否应该有一个披风?
Should it have a cape or no cape?
是否应该有一个面罩?
Should you have a mask or no mask?
最终 我只留下了最基本的
Eventually, I just boiled it down to the basics
「我需要一套可以自由活动的服装
Ineeded a costume where I was free to move.
我需要保护我的身体
所以我做了这个覆盖了皮革和锁子甲的紧身上衣
So I did this with a tunic that was covered in leather and mail...
锁子甲就是一种钢丝网
我的兜帽也是皮革和铁丝网做的
然后是三角裤 它们覆盖了同样的锁子甲
And then briefs. They were covered in the same mail.
我已经把头发遮住了 我只需要一个小面罩
所以我做了这个面罩
So I did it wit this ; is the mask.
我在面罩上粘了一层化妆胶水
I attached this mask with a spirit gum...
结果当时有好几个蒙面英雄
LPEPER: It turned out, there were several masked adventurers at the tin
是的 在我初次登场大约一个月后
MASON: Yeah, about a month after I made my debut...
头条新闻都是关于一个叫剪影的年轻女子
...the headlines were all about a young woman called the Silhouette.
她揭露了一个经营儿童色情制品的无耻出版商
She had exposed a crooked publisher who was dealing in child pornography.
她还痛扁了他和他的两个摄影师 对吧?
d she gave him such a brutal beating. Him and his two cameramen, rig
她还痛扁了他和他的两个摄影师对吧?
这是一个很好的故事
Well, that was quite a story
从那时起蒙面英雄数量开始迅速增加
有很多关于一个穿得像飞蛾的人的故事
There were stories of a man dressed like a moth...
他可以在空中滑翔
...who could glide through the air.
后来有一个穿着黄色连衣裤的人的故事
就是那个特别野蛮凶残的
who was particularly brutal and vicious.
兜帽判官戏剧性登场的12个月内
至少有另外七个变装义警
有莎莉·朱庇特 人称丝魂
还有美钞、蛾人
There was Dollar Bill, there was Mothman.
剪影、笑匠
..there was the Silhouette, there was Comedian
当然了 还有我
And, of course, there was me.
梅森告诉我的事几乎都写在他的书里了
Little that Mason told me was not already in his book.
所以我转向他的世界里的其他人物 以了解更多信息
So I turned to some of the other figures from his world to find out more.
New York City Mayor Gordon B
City Council in congratula
outstanding service to the comm
New York City Mayor Gordon Brunner unit
City Council in congratulating Jupit
outstanding service to the commuFor c
at the risk of her life above and beyond t
ew York City Mayor Gordon Brunner unues
ity Council in congratulating SallJupiter
utstanding service to the communit con
the risk of her life above and beyond the
York City Mayor
Council in congratulating Sally piter A
WW
tanding service to the community. Sons
he risk of her life above and beyond the
Council in congratulating Sally Jupiter A.K
anding service to the community. spic
e risk of her life above and beyond the cal
她利用她的性感打击犯罪。
而且她的打击罪犯生涯延展到了大银幕上
现在她的女儿靠她的影像生活
生活似乎抛弃了莎莉·朱庇特
...and life seemingly has passed Sally Jupiter by.
1975年 我们在她家和她进行了以下交流
We joined her at her home for the following exchange back in 1975.
为什么取名丝魂?
CULPEPER: Why the name Silk Spectre?
很多人都猜测过为什么我会想出这个名字
Many people have hypothesized about reasons why that might have come up
y people have hypothesized about reasons why that might have com
而实际上我想找到一个神秘的名字
而实际上 我想找到一个神秘的名字
ag Ane And in truthwanted to find something mysterious... order, despite
我觉得她应该是一个可以从你手中溜走的人
And I felt that she should be somebody who could slip out of your hands
我想只是因为丝魂很好听 我能说的就这些了
And it just had a good ring to it, I guess, is all I can really say.
你成为蒙面英雄的动机是什么?
What were your motivations in becoming a masked adventurer?
我看到了兜帽判官
I saw Hooded Justice...
我就有了做一些不同寻常的事情的想法
...and I think the idea of doing something that was out of the normal-
我从来都不觉得自己很合群
我觉得成为丝魂让我感觉更
如今丝魂以相当不雅的形象出现在海报和漫画中
Now, Silk Spectre is presented in fairly racy imagery in posters and in comics.
你是如何看待这些视觉上有辱人格的图片的?
How do you deal with these, what I call, visually degrading pictures?
我对那种事从来没有意见
oh, I never had a problem with that sort of thing
我是说他们总是把我当作性感偶像
I mean, you know, they always referred to me as a sex symbol.
我不得不说 我宁愿成为那种象征
And I have to say, I'd rather be a symbol of that...
你明白我的意思吗?
吉米·范图奇一个著名的暴徒 你肯定听说过他
Jimmy Fantucci, a famous mobster, I'm sure you've heard of him.
吉米·范图奇 一个著名的暴徒 你肯定听说过他
因为他不忍心向我开枪,他竟然当了警察
因为他不忍心向我开枪 他竟然当了警察
He actually turned himself into the cops because he couldn't shoot me.
就像我说的 我从不回避我的外表
You know, as I said, I never shied away from the way that I looked
know, as I said, I never shied away from the way that I look
事实上 在这种情况下 我可以利用这一点
And, in fact, it seemed in this case, I could use it.
蒙面英雄 或者随便你想叫他们什么 他们都是和商业有关的
Well, masked adventurers or whatever what you wanna call them is all about commerce.
你必须记住这个国家是建立在娱乐的基础上的
to remember that this founded on entertainme
当我经营莎莉 也就是丝魂的时候
And when I managed Sally, the Silk Spectre...
我们利用她变装英雄的身份做各种有利可图的交易
...we used her status as a costumed hero to make lucrative deals of every kind.
电影交易、图片授权、漫画书等
这是一种企业几乎会立刻接受的商业策略
美钞原本是堪萨斯大学的明星运动员
当他们意识到拥有自己的超级英雄
是一个有趣的宣传前景时
-家大型百货公司雇用了美钞
..was an interesting publicity prospect.
尽管如此我还是认为我和莎莉是这个概念的先驱
Still, like to think that'Sally and_l pioneered the concept.
当你试图在世界上留下印记时 你需要帮助
When you're thing to make a marke the world you need help
你需要一个有凝聚力的人
·让公众意识到这一点 他确实做到
·我认为事实上,可能是以牺牲许多人的议题为代价“
关于变装英雄对社会是好是坏的价值判断
这就像问电视是好是坏一样
答案是两者都存在
The answer is that it's both.
问题才开始出现
..that the problems started.
民兵组织 没错
The Minutemen, yeah.
真是个好主意
What a great idea.
我希望我能把这个功劳占为己有 但凭良心讲我不能
I wish I can take credit for it, but I can't in good conscience
事情的经过是这样的:
The way it happened was..
有一天,我收到了一封大都会队长给莎莉的信
...one day I got a letter for Sally from Captain Metropolis.
I note also from my perusat he
ther 我收到了一封大都会队长给苏者的信
ur persuasion stepping:
day I got a letter i Captain
EC
I note also from my perusal 73 1 he
her poup1 我收到了一封大都 给莎莉的信
rstepping 1
one day Loot a lette
I note also from my perusal he p
队长给莎莉的信
ter pee  tupping r
er peel,我收到了一封大都会以给沙ing
r poo隔天,我收到了一封大都会队长给莎莉的高ing
r peep一天,我收到了一封大都会队长给莎莉的信ng for
people 我收到了一封大都会队长给的信呫 for
te also from my perusal of the ress tl
ple of our persuasion steppingward
他说他想聚在一起讨论
ierisa, and, being niittary man by nai
te also from my perusal of the press th
ple of our persuasion steppingard
他说他想聚在一起讨论
eries, and, being iiitary man by nat
te also from my perusal of the press th
WW
le of our persuasion steppingard
他说他想聚
ories, and, tury man by nati
e also from my perusal of the press the
WW
le of our persuasion stepping 5rd 1
rles, and, 他说他想聚在 man by natu
扫路
said he w gether to discuss the
also from my perusal of the press tha
WW
of our persuasion stepping 5rd
Grd ti
dea, and, 他現他想聚起冷 n by natu:
他说他聚在一起诃 i
al an fro perisa.l of the press. thit
our persuasio stepping fo ed tic
and, be说他想聚在一起讨论an y nature
1, 一个蒙面英雄团伙的想法
bur persuasion stepping forward join
ind, bvg a military man and
: might be 团队法
trategic advanta
ur persuasion stepping forward
nd, be vg military man by and
英雄团队
might be a distinct vtrategic advantag
ar persuasioi stepping forward
nd, be military man by ni and
自由
might be a sti le advantag
“起初我以为他只 生意把她上
然后我做了一
我意识到我的担忧
无稽之
如果你明白我的意思(大都会队长与兜帽判官是同性恋关系)
..if you get my meaning.
劳伦斯成就了民兵组织
Lawrence made the Minutemen.
如果不是因为他和他的宣传技巧
我是说我认为作为你这个行业的人 你可能会理解
I mean I think as someone in your profession, you could probably understand...
如果我们做了这个采访 但是没有人看到
...that if we did this interview and no one saw it...
那么噗 这就不重要了
...then, poof, it doesn't matter.
我意识到如果没有偶尔的花招
来重振萎靡不振的公众兴趣
即使是那些穿得像莎莉的变装英雄
公众对他们的一时狂热最终也会消退
...would eventually fade, even the ones dressed like Sally,
经过一番考虑 我建议他们在公报上刊登一个大广告
After some consideration I suggested they take a large ad out in the Gazette...
请求更多的神秘人站出来
sking for more mystery men to come forwa
这就是民兵组织的由来
夜枭、剪影和其他人时
..Nite Owl, Silhouette and the others.
你是怎么想的?你害怕吗?
...what were your thoughts? Were you intimidated?
有一种解脱的感觉吗?
Was there a conce of rolinf?
我不得不说那是一段令人无比振奋的时光
Oh, it was an incredibly exhilarating time, I have to say.
我们都觉得自己是这个家庭的一部分
让我们觉得自己是有价值的地方
where we could feel like we actually were of value.
每个人都给民兵组织带来了不同的东西
Everyone brought something different to the Minutemen.
但不知何故 当我们在一起的时候我们都相信自己在做的事情
But somehow when we were together there was a bonding feeling.
这让我们产生了一种亲密感
..that we all believed in what we were doing.
现在 我说“解脱”的原因是
那时候许多人认为你们都是很奇怪的、不正常的人
穿着儿童服装到处跑人
running around in children's costume
我们只是普通人
JUPITER: We were just peopl
每个人都有完全不同的政治目的
And everabilities
Moreveryone did have absolutely different politics.
as they
我们中有些人是为了出名 有些人是为了权力
re progranSom of us were in it for fame. Some for power.
有些是为了躲避世界上的其他人
但最终 我们的政治目的对我们想在那里做的事情
But in the end of the day, our politics really didn't get in the way too much...
并没有太多的阻碍这是好事
我们在各自的社区里做了很多好事 结果却一败涂地
We did too much good in our respective communities just to be written off.
我们都试图通过自己的努力
We were all attempting through our personal efforts..
使我们的国家成为一个更好、更安全的居住地
..to make our country a better and a safer place to live.
很明显 霍利斯·梅森是一个从不为自己的生活
Clearly, Hollis Mason is a man who makes no apologies...
是否足以成为他戴上面具、主持治安的正当理由?
...for donning a mask and dispensing vigilante justice?
我走出去四处打听 以便更好地了解
I went out and asked around to get a better sense...
你们这些普通人对蒙面英雄的看法
..of how you, the people, felt about masked heroes.
我不知道
MAN 1: I don't know.
我有很多顾客都是警察
Lanta lot of customers that are con
那些从我这里买了一包烟的家伙
that come by and pay for a pack of smokes from me eve
他们告诉我这些蒙面英雄
nd they tell me that these masked adventure
他们让工作变得更困难了
...they're making the job more difficult.
我觉得他们怎么样?
我可以告诉你 他们几乎毁了我的生意
They've just about destroyed my business, I can tell you that.
他们伤害了我的顾客
They maim my customers.
他们喜欢折断手指 他们认为这很有趣
They like to break fingers. They think it's funny.
没错 他们很危险
Yeah. They're dangerous.
但另一方面 如果我们没有
But then on the other hand, what if we hadn't ha
曼哈顿博士那样的人站在我们这边呢?
...that Dr. Manhattan guy on our side, huh?
我是说我知道这对我们来说是不可思议的
I mean, I know it's inconceivable to us, now knowing what we know
但谁能说没有他们
越南的情况就不会一样呢?
...without them?E
如果在这场战争中战败
那会毁了我们的国家
That would've destroyed our country.
更多关于变装英雄和围绕他们的争议的话题
More on costumed adventurers and the controversy surrounding them..
将在赞助商的广告后播出
after this word from our sponsors
精工宣布世界上第一款数字石英表 液晶计时表
它可以显示时间、日期
只要按下一个按鈕它就能变成一个秒表
可以在十分之一秒内记录两次时间
当你再次按下按鈕时 保存在电子存储器中的时间就会重新出现
精工液晶计时表
The Seiko liquid crystal chronogra
唯一的精工超凡数字石英表
one of Seiko's superb digital quart watch
欢迎回来 感谢大家的收看
Welcome back, and thank you for watching.
在目前的情况下 与蒙面英雄 也就是守望者
In our current climate, the relevance of masked adventurers, the Watchmen...
相关联的问题比以往任何时候都多
...is more in question than ever before.
我们现在继续回顾我们的节目
在节目中我们讨论了
...in which we discussed Under the Hood...
前任蒙面英雄夜枭一 -霍利斯·梅森的回忆录《面罩之下》
...a memoir of original masked hero The Nite Owl, née Hollis Mason.
一这本书引发了我们今天关于
A book which precipitated many of the questions we have today...
违反我们规定的法律行动的这些蒙面英雄的许多疑问
...about these men and women who act apart from our prescribed laws of justice.
events point to global wa
calation Massive Nat761
当然 也有英雄值得研uard calle
numbers are many
would make for fascine
events point to global wa
calation Massive •NatiwEl
number 当然,也有许多变装英進值得uard calle
ber revise who would mak
当然也有许多变装英雄值得研究
nts point to globe wo
on Massive National
s who woul
为了获得一些专业的见解
I spoke with psychiatrist William Long...
我和精神病学家威廉·朗进行了交谈
...to gain some professional insight.
这是一个有趣的问题
You know, it's an interesting question.
大多数时候 我在监狱里和罪犯一起工作
with arinsicale
所以我的看法有点偏颇
So my perception is slightly skewed.
我认为肯定有蒙面英雄
think certainly there are masked heroes..
declaring Dr Manhattan
还有超人类 比如曼哈顿博士6
is very US domination
我认为还有一些人只 as a sec
weapon. Dipromatic channels hav
think there are others that are nothing amore than couuripals.
Bac hac ma
我认为还有一些人只不过是罪犯
dem
weapon. Diplomatic chan
nk there are others that are nothing more than crimper
Soviet Foreign Minn
MRO我认为还有一些人只不过是罪犯
edares th
over U
there are others that are nothing more thankenkas
我认为还有一些人只不过是靠
ARCHES
我认为还有一些人只不过是罪犯
think there are others that are nothing more than criminal
为他们的暴力倾向辩护
...to justify their violent tendencies.
唯一构成真正威胁的蒙面英雄
是少数真的相信自己在做好事的
边缘反社会者
that actually believe that they are doing good
在面罩之下
Beneath that mask....
他们就像你和我
望、恐惧
充满希望、欲望、
...with hopes and desires, fears...
还有爱
...love.
我希望有一天
I hope that one day...
我可以对其中一位蒙面英雄进行心理分析
...can psychoanalyze one of these masked heroes.
那将是一件了不起的事。
That would be something.
对我们来说这似乎是一个过去的时代
It seems a bygone era to us now.
咆哮的40年代令人振奋的日子
The heady days of the roaring '40s.
人们渴望消遣 渴望戏剧
还有什么比一群自己设计的超级英雄
表演一出夸张的街头打击犯罪的戏剧更棒的呢?
在一个超级恶棍横行的世界里
And in a world populated by supervillains....
为什么不呢?
...why not?
有臭名昭著的神秘主义者摩洛克
There was the notorious Moloch the Mystic.
使用杂耍新奇的魔术表演来面对他一 人的恐怖浪潮
当然后来出现了像大块头这样的现代超级反派
那个身材矮小的犯罪大师正在市监狱服无期徒刑
...the diminutive master criminal now serving a life sentence in the city jail.
你认为我是威胁
Vou think I'm tha
我不是戴着面具的人 我没什么好隐瞒的
I'm not the one wearing a mask. I got nothing to hide
那种戴着面具的是什么样的人?
What kind of person is that? Wear a mask?
我是个受人尊敬的商人
I'm a respectable businessman.
找到神秘主义者摩洛克并不容易
CULPEPER: It wasn't easy finding Moloch the Mystic.
不过话说回来也不是太难
But then again, well, it wasn't too difficult.
摩洛克 就像战后许多声名狼藉的人物一样
You see, Moloch, like so many infamous figures of our postwar past....
他们仅仅是进入了平民生活
...had simply gone into civilian life.
我那时比较年轻
MOLOCH: I was a younger man then.
MOLOCH: I was a younger man ther
我很叛逆
I was rebellious.
就像你在附近看到的这些帮派一样 Knot Tops黑帮
Like these gangs you see around, the Knot Tops.
当你生活在一个有着超人类权威人物的世界里
When you live in a world with superhuman authority figures...
如果你想反抗 你必须进行更大规模的反抗
and you wanna rebel, you have to rebel on a larger scale.
你得把事件升级
ou have to escalate things, you se
所以
So...
如果你成长在一个有超级英雄的世界里 你想要反抗
...if you grow up in a world with superheroes and you wanna rebel...
你必须成为一个超级反派
...you have to become a supervillain.
所以没错 我认为没有超级英雄的社会会更好
So, yeah, I think society is better off without the superheroes...
因为这也意味着不需要超级反派
because that means there's no need for any supervillains eithe
这种狂热持续了不到10年
You know, it didn't last, oh, 10 years.
当50年代到来的时候 人们对变装英雄的看法
When the '50s came, the whole perception of costumed adventurers...
完全改变了 你知道吗?
...you know, changed, you know?
那只是一时流行的狂热
It was a fad, yeah.
这种狂热正在消失 而我们也在随之消亡
And the fad was dying out and we were dying with it.
莎莉
Sally...
她怀孕后就离开了
...well, she got pregnant and she lef
我们其余的人被迫
The rest of us, we were forced to testif
在众议院非美活动委员会面前作证
..before the House Un-American Activities Committee.
这是一场政治迫害
It was a witch hunt.
我们都被迫向其中一位众议院议员
We were all forced to reveal our identities...
透露自己的身份>
..to one of its representatives.
我是民兵组织的大都会队长
幸运的是大都会队长有着杰出的军事履历
N: Now, luckily, with Captain Metropolis having such an outstanding milita
以及我在警察部门的工作
...and with my own service in the police force...
我们都或多或少很快就消除了怀疑
蛾人遇到了更多的困难
Mothman met with more difficulty.
主要是因为他在学生时代结交的左翼朋友们
hostly because of the left-wing friends that he'd cultivated during his student
现在他终于被澄清了
Now, he's eventually cleared...
但是调查过程漫长残酷
我认为他因此承受的压力
that I think that the pressure he was under
最终导致他精神崩溃
1.
NEW YORK. NY
兜帽判官
拒绝作证
因为他不准备向任何人透露他的真实身份
the grounds that he was not prepared to reveal his true identity to any
当他们向他施压时
And when they pressed him
他消失了
...he disappeared.
我对他的这一行为充满了敬意
And I really respect him for that.
他是我成为夜枭的原因
was the rancan I harama the Mita Oul
直到今天我都不知道面罩后的那个人是谁
...and I don't know to this day who he was behind that mask.
很有趣 不是吗?
Isn't that something?
我明白你想离开民兵组织是因为你怀孕了
understand that you wanted to leave the Minutemen because you got pregnar
但这是唯一的原因吗?
But is that the only reason?
你从民兵组织退休还有其他原因吗?
有时候是时候往前看了
如果我没有怀孕的话 我想我会呆得更久
“但是生活给了你一些什么时候该离开的信号
这就是其中一个原因
u know, and that seemed to be the o
在霍利斯的传记中 他声称你被笑匠性侵了
his biography, Hollis alleged that you were sexually assaulted by The Come
但你从来没提过这件事
Yet you've never said anything about this.
为什么我现在要打破一生的习惯呢?
你作为一个记者问这个问题 我不会指责你
Fran't blame you fo
但是无可奉告
莎莉·朱庇特和笑匠之间的那件事
much did the incident between Sally Jupiter and The Comed
对你决定挂起面罩有多大影响?
affect your decision to hand in the mack?
有很大的关系 没错
Well, that had lot to do with it, yeah.
我认为一旦你意识到你的一些队友
I think once you realize that some of your teammates..
和你要追捕的罪犯一样堕落扭曲
just as depraved and twisted as the criminals you're going
没错
Yeah.
这和我退出有很大关系
That had a lot to do with why I quit.
那就是个谣言
here's no truth to that rumor.
如果发生了像这样的事
If something like that had happened...
你不认为我会建议莎莉提出刑事指控吗?
她是我最好的客户 我最大的收入来源
She was my best client. My biggest earner.
我绝不会让那样的事情逍遥法外
would never allow something like that to go unpunishe
这不过是哗众取宠、自我推销罢了
It's nothing more than sensationalism, self-promotion)
霍利斯·梅森想卖出更多的书
在我把雪茄塞进你眼睛之前 把那东西从我脸上拿开
Get that thing out of my face before I put my cigar out in your eye.
《面罩之下》是一本很棒的书
Under the Hood is a fantastic book.
他是我的一个顾客
know, he's one of my customers, you
我经常见到他
I see him all the time.
关于超级英雄的这个问题很有趣 这是一个非常微妙的界限
It's funny about this superhero thing, you know it's a very fine line.
当你遇到像夜枭这样在你心目中是超级英雄的人
I when you got somebody like the Nite Owl who is your quintessential supe
因为外面的这个家伙
because outside you get this guy....
他变装后做各种各样爆炸之类的事
.who dresses up and does all the kaboom-kabang stuff
但他内心是个警察
所以他知道什么是忠诚守信 你明白我的意思吗?
So he's a guy who knows what's true blue. You know what I mean?
他不喜欢这些附庸风雅的东西
He's not into these kind of artsy-fartsy things.
他是个了不起的人
He's a great man.
所以
So..
我不知道
...I don't know.
很难说这些蒙面英雄是好是坏
值得注意的是早在1975年
It's interesting to note that back in 1975...
人们对于这些所谓的变装英雄对社会是利是弊
...people were still very much divided as to whether or not...
鉴于这次采访播出后的事件
Given the events after this interview aired...
或许霍利斯·梅森的退休来得正是时候
...perhaps Hollis Mason's retirement came at the perfect time.
在这次广告时间后 我们会听到更多来自霍利斯·梅森的消息
We'll hear more from Hollis Mason after this commercial break.
为什么这么多人选择萨尼清洁剂
「ANNOUNCER: Why do so many choose Sani-Flush
而不是其它领先的马桶清洁剂?
萨尼清洁剂有额外的功能
可以清洁马桶内部 并把马桶拐弯处清洁干净
延时摄影显示萨尼清洁剂与它额外的功能
Time-lapse shows Sani-Flush, with its extra power.
可以在马桶内部以及拐弯处
...cleans away rust stains and deposits...
萨尼清洁剂具有杀死数百万细菌的能力
萨尼清洁剂 清洁马桶内部和拐弯处
购买粉末或液体的萨尼清洁剂
现在继续我对霍利斯·梅森的采访
Continuing now with my interview of Hollis Mason.
我们正在谈论变装英雄
We're talking about costumed adventurers.
他被称为世界第八大奇迹三
been cau
也被称为世界第八大奇迹
He's been called the Eighth Wonder of the World.
他被称为世界第八大奇迹
我们的国宝 我们最大的希望
Our national treasure, Our greatest hope
但是曼哈顿博士也被视为一个怪胎
But Dr Manhattan wed a folk of nature
他的力量是如此之大
His power is so great as to illicit fear...
以至于不仅使我们的敌人 而且使我们自己都感到恐惧
...not only in our enemies but in ourselves.
在他成为今天这个散发着光芒的蓝色超人类之前。
他是乔恩·奥斯特曼 物理学家 一个钟表匠的儿子
she was Jon Osterman, physicist, son of a watchmaker.
一个有着友谊、爱情和普通家庭价值观的人
A man with friendships, loves, common family values.
他的一个朋友 实际上
他的一个朋友 实际上是同事
One of his friends and, in fact, colleagues...
如今仍在和曼哈顿博士一起工作
who continuing to with Dr Manhattan today
他本身就是一位受人尊敬的物理学家
...is an esteemed physicist in his own right...
沃利·韦弗
...Wally Weaver.
我们去了韦弗的实验室进行了以下交谈
We went to Weaver's lab and had the following conversation.
我认为
Well, I think.
各种各样的英雄都是好的
heroes of all kinds are a good-thing.
我说的是我们军队中英勇的男男女女
nd I'm talking about the brave men and women of our Armed Forc
我说的是警察和消防员
talking about the policemen and the firefighter
我说的是科学家和医生
Im talking about the scientists and the doctors. And, uh...
我会把蒙面英雄也算在
Yeah, I'd include masked heroes
对社会有益的群体里
In that group that's a benefit to society t
抱歉 曼哈顿博士
I'm sorry. Dr. Manhattan...
完全是另一回事
...is something else entirely.
我正在写一本关于他如何永远改变地缘政治格局的书。
I'm writing a book about how he's changed the geopolitical landscape forever...
从本质上来说战争的概念已经过时了
...essentially making the very idea of war obsolete.
第一反应就是完全不相信
You know, the first thing was absoluterd
当然我也很高兴
purse, as you know, there was e
我是说这就像圣诞老人不仅活着 而且活得很好
I mean, it was like Santa Claus was alive and thriving arved at the there f
但恐惧
But the fear....
那是一种可怕的恐惧
It was a terrible fear...
以及一种直达你内心深处的不确定性
...and an uncertainty that went right to your core.
我当然理解一辆旧车
I certainly understood how an old car feels...
看到一款新车推出时的感受
...when it sees a new car, a new model come rolling out.
但还不止这些
But it was more than that.
我想我可以把这种感觉归结为三个单词
You know, I think I can boil the feeling down to three words, really. It's
我们已经被取代了
We've been replaced.
我指的是人类
I mean, humanity.
我们已经被取代了
We've been replaced.
霍利斯总是有戏剧天赋
毫无疑问 这件事震惊了我们所有人
here is no doubt that it was an absolute shock to all of
任何事物都可以像曼哈顿博士一样存在
「我是说这对我们来说是超出理解范围的事物
品
我是说这对我们来说是超出理解范围的事物
I mean, this was something out of the realm of concept for us.
但是我们永远需要人类
「就像我们在技术上的扩张和发展一样
我们仍然需要人与人之间的接触 你明白吗?
We still need human contact, you know?
人们总是曲解我对乔恩的评价
People have always misinterpreted what I said about Jon.
我没有把他比作上帝“我不是说他是神
wasn't comparing him to God. I wasn't saying he was a god.
我真希望我没说过那样的话
just-- Just wish I wouldn't have ever said that.
底线是:乔恩仍然是乔恩
Bottom line is this: Jon is still Jon.
他骨子里仍然是个人类。
At his core he's still a man.
就拿我说的超级反派是对超级英雄的出现
Well, take what I said about supervillains being a direct response..
并将其应用到当前的情况中
and annly that to the current conarin
如果有一个仅凭一个想法就能摧毁万物的存在
If you have a being that can destroy with a single thought...
很快就会有一个与之相对立的对手
...or there soon will be, a counterpoint or an adversary to that being
宇宙有办法找到它自己的平衡
The universe has a way of finding its own equilibrium, its own level
让我担心的是 曼哈顿博士的死敌很快就会到来
What worries me is that Dr. Manhattanisinemesis will be arriving soon.
当然其中一些蒙面英雄
f course, some of these masked adventurer
从未停止练习他们独特的技艺
...never stopped practicing their unique craft.
最终 随着时间流逝 他们的出现再次受到欢迎
ventually time moved forward to a point where their presence was again welcome
有些人会说这是迫切需要的
and come would cou coraly nondod
大城市的街道充斥着暴力、恐吓和猖獗的犯罪
Big city streets festered with violence intimidation and rampant crime.
一个新一代的蒙面英雄出现的完美环境
当然我说的是守望者
Of course, I speak of the Watchmen.
现在 随着冷战的升级和一个真正超人类的存在
Now, with the Cold War escalating and the presence of a truly super being..
出现在我们的国防前沿
...at the forefront of our national defense...
the forefront of our national defonc
越来越多的恐惧和不安情绪似乎弥漫在人群中
...a growing fear and restlessness seems to permeate the population.
只是这一次 我们害怕的不是罪犯
Only this time the faar is not of the criminals
而是打击犯罪分子本身
..but of the crime fighters themselves.
基恩参议员肯定认为是时候结束蒙面行动了
linepartments
基恩参议员肯定认为是时候结束蒙面行动局
他提出的新法律将有效地限制这些变装英雄们
is suggested new laws would effectively clip the wings of these costumed heroe
迫使他们挂起面罩
making them hang up their masks
基恩参议员是一个机会主义者
Senator Keene is an opportunistic...
一个无足轻重的人
...cipher.
他根本不知道自己在说什么
He has no idea what he's talking about
has his way, our streets
will soon be without the
long standing presence 75
在说什么
of the vigilante group
如果他们能像这些蒙面英雄一样
那我们一开始就不需要
e wouldn't need people like Senator
那我们一开始就不需要。
像基恩参议员这样的人了
我对基恩参议员有什么看法?
What do I think about Senator Keene?
听着 我每天都在这里工作
Listen, I work down here every day.
每当我遇到麻烦或者有人在这里打我时
never I'm in trouble, whenever somebody's down here beating m
我大喊救命 我不在乎谁来救我
ad I yell for help, I don't care who comes to save my
我不在乎他是超级英雄还是警察
don't care if it's a superhero. I don't care if it's a coo
只要我喊救命的时候有人来就行
As long as somebody comes when I'm yelling "help
你明白吗?
You understand?
People have.
`需要
..a need for
一个平凡的英雄
...an everyday hero.
无论是蒙面英雄还是其他的
而且
And, uh...
一个能够明辨是非的人
people who know right from wrong...
people who know right from wrong.
永远都是被需要的
will always be in demand.
to the efforts of 'Mothman and his vigilante friends "The finally been caug
The Metro Bank Bandits have finally been caug efforts of Mothman' and his vigilante
friends Terrytemen.
No Mothman aid in
cis, he then
sting operation orchestrated by The Minutemen's took the time the victims
hank bandits have been captured. apprehend "There is hope," re-assured th
'.
conducted Metro New York
CA
JULL
he efforts of 'Mothman' and his vigilante friends "The finally been caught, thank
The Metro Bank Bandits have finally been caught, than
efforts of othman' and his vi
Sinutemen
friend Mothman
ucchestrated by The Minutemen's
aspects,
have been captured, apprehend
Metro Cemre is hope," re-ass
utemen'
The Metro Bank Bandits have finally been caught, thanks took the time to help the
he efforts of 'Mothman' and his vigilante friends 'The finally been caught, thanks
shman and his v
efforis WW inutemen
Mothma
frien MM
uspects
heen captured apprehending
Blemen' orchestrated by The  took the time to help the is hope," re-as
rents, the Metro Central Bank Crime Ring ha
g havoc on the city
en caught, thanks to the efforts of 'Mothman and his
WW its
llante friends 'The Minutemen'.
No only did
caning havoc on the city
sidents, the Metro Central Bank Crime Ring ha
en caught, thanks to the efforts of 'Mothman' and hi
dlante friends 'The Minutemen
No only
weaking havoc on the ci
dents, the Metro Central Bank Crime Ring have a
n caught, thanks to the efforts of 'Mothman)
MM
ante friends 'The Minutem
wreaking havoc on the
nts, the Metro Central Bank Crime Ring have finall
aught, thanks to the efforts of Math
te friends or wreaking havoc on the
nts the Metro Central Bank Crime Ring have finall
d i
caught, thanks to the efforts of ur
teles wreaking havoc on the
Metro Central Bank Crime Ring have
WWW
ght, thanks to the offer
inventory weapons at headquarters
我想在这里说点私人的话题
I want to get a little personal here for the mome
你从没结过婚 这是为什么?
You never married. Why is that?
呃
Um....
谢谢
Thank you
我想如果有什么原因导致我没有结婚的话
Well, I suppose if there's any one reason why I never got married...
是因为
..it was because...
莎莉·朱庇特和别人结婚了
...well, Sally Jupiter was taken.
我不认为我对她有感觉是什么天大的秘密
I don't think it's any great secret that I had a thing for her.
我不认为我对他有感觉是什么天大的秘密
有一半的男人喜欢她
Half the male population did.
等我鼓足勇气约她出去的时候
the time I'd rustled up the courage to ask her out on a proper dat
她已经和她的经纪人结婚了
...she was already married to her manager.
每当我想到这件事的时候都会觉得很有趣
It's kind of funny when you think of it.
我打扮成猫头鹰 每天冒着生命危险
I dress up as an owl and risk my life on a daily basis...
但说到约女孩出去
...but when it came to asking a girl out...
这超出了我的能力范围
it was more than could mana
可悲的是 我认为我们的婚姻从一开始就注定要失败
我在莎莉生活中的职业地位使我很难成为一个好丈夫
作为她的经纪人
It was my job as her manager...
我的工作不仅要接受男人被她吸引这一事实
...to not only accept the fact that men were attracted to her...
而冒还要依赖这种吸引力
来赚取利益
..to prey upon it.
霍利斯对你来说非常重要
Hollis was very important to you.
他是你生命中非常重要的人 对吗?
He was a very important person in your life, correct?
绝对的
Absolutely.
没错 我们还在联系
We do. We do.
我得说 没有我想要的那么多
你的生活把你引向不同的方向
ou know, your life takes you in different direction
但那确实是一段奇妙的时光
but that was really a magical, magical time..
...but that was really a magical, magical time..
...and we do like to talk about the old times when we get together
夜枭和丝魂总有一天会在一起
...half-baked idea that...
当我们最初与霍利斯·梅森交谈时
When we originally spoke with Hollis Mason...
以及和蒙面英雄团体的其他成员一起留下的遗产
将会持续很多年
...would live on for years to come.
他不知道自己错得有多离谱
He could not have known how wrong he was.
这是当我们出于我们的道德观
has been a nostalgic look back at a colorful time in this nation's pa
转向穿着卡通服装的华丽英雄时
when we turned to flamboyant heroes with cartoonish outfits
对这个国家过去丰富多彩的时光的怀旧回顾
...for our moral outlook.
在后基恩法案时代 我们现在生活在一个
In the post-Keene Act world we now live in...
蒙面英雄已经过时且无关紧要的世界
...the masked heroes are as outdated and irrelevant...
就像霍利斯·梅森在他的汽修店里修理的旧的破烂车一样
...as the old beat-up wrecks that Hollis Mason works on in his garage.
我们希望你会发现这次回顾的变装英雄的历史
We hope that you have found this look back at the history of costumed adventurers
既有启发性又有教育意义
...both enlightening and informative.
我是拉里·卡尔佩珀 这里是The Culpeper Minute
I'm Larry Culpeper for The Culpeper Minute.